<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on cyber stuff &amp; half-working projects</title><link>https://percevalsa.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on cyber stuff &amp; half-working projects</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percevalsa.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blue Screen Of Death (BSOD) is dead, long live the BSOD</title><link>https://percevalsa.github.io/posts/death-of-the-blue-screen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percevalsa.github.io/posts/death-of-the-blue-screen/</guid><description>BSOD is dead Microsoft killed the blue screen of death. It has been with us for 35 years and has changed form and text many times. It will be a black screen, as we can see in a screenshot from the blog post The Windows Resiliency Initiative: Building resilience for a future-ready enterprise. So we can keep speaking of BSOD, but it will be a black screen from now on.</description></item><item><title>Auto switch between light and dark mode on GNOME</title><link>https://percevalsa.github.io/posts/gnome-auto-dark-mode/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percevalsa.github.io/posts/gnome-auto-dark-mode/</guid><description>I want my Fedora 42 (works with 41 I guess) to automatically switch to dark mode at night and light mode during the day. I&amp;rsquo;m already using the night mode to trigger the blue light filter at specific times.
Thanks to Adam I had a base to start with. He wrote a blog post on having the dark mode auto switch with hard coded times. You can read it here</description></item><item><title>Open Windows URL shortcut in Linux</title><link>https://percevalsa.github.io/posts/open-mswinurl-in-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percevalsa.github.io/posts/open-mswinurl-in-linux/</guid><description>Introduction I am working on a robot project with my brother. We share data (datasheets, pictures&amp;hellip;) in a folder synchronized on dropbox. He only uses Windows and I am mainly using Linux (debian based distros with GNOME Desktop Environment to be precise). He tends to use Windows URL files to save web shortcut in a sharable way. But those files are not openable by default in Linux. I want to open those .</description></item><item><title>macOS configuration after a fresh install</title><link>https://percevalsa.github.io/posts/macos-configuration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percevalsa.github.io/posts/macos-configuration/</guid><description>Don&amp;rsquo;t write .DS_Store file on removable devices:
defaults write com.apple.desktopservices DSDontWriteNetworkStores -bool true\ defaults write com.apple.desktopservices DSDontWriteUSBStores -bool true\ Install custom host file to make internet safer
cp hosts hosts.bak sudo cp hosts hosts.bak sudo cp /Users/perceval/Workspace/hosts/alternates/fakenews-gambling-porn/hosts /etc/hosts sudo dscacheutil -flushcache;sudo killall -HUP mDNSResponder udo killall mDNSResponderHelper sudo cp /etc/hosts.new /etc/hosts sudo killall -HUP mDNSResponder sudo killall mDNSResponderHelper sudo dscacheutil -flushcache sudo launchctl start mDNSResponder head /etc/hosts add a command line access to sublime text</description></item><item><title>librespot on piCorePlayer</title><link>https://percevalsa.github.io/posts/librespot-picore-player/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percevalsa.github.io/posts/librespot-picore-player/</guid><description>Introduction All the code is available in my github repo
I wanted a stable headless Spotify player for my living room. It has to run on a RaspberryPi and boot fast in order to turn it on only when needed with a switch. One of the solution would be Volumio or HifiBerry but they take too much time to boot. piCorePlayer is a good alternative but it has too much stuff installed by default and the Spotify extension is based on an outdated extension.</description></item><item><title>Run a X11 app in a devcontainer on wayland only distro</title><link>https://percevalsa.github.io/posts/devcontainer-x11-wayland/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percevalsa.github.io/posts/devcontainer-x11-wayland/</guid><description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m running fedora after running Ubuntu for a long time. For a project I need to run a X11 application in a devcontainer. This devcontainer needs an access to the Xauthority file in order to display items on the screen. On ubuntu, and .Xauthority file is automatically created by the gnome session in the home folder of the user. But on fedora, the .Xauthority file is created in /run/user/1000/ and not in the home folder.</description></item><item><title>Yocto build on external SSD in devcontainers</title><link>https://percevalsa.github.io/posts/yocto-cache-ssd/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percevalsa.github.io/posts/yocto-cache-ssd/</guid><description>I manage and build multiple yocto distributions at work. The performances guidelines advise to use another disk than the one the system is running on. As I have a laptop I only have one internal SSD. Therefore I need to use an external SSD to store my yocto files (downloads in DL_DIR , build in TMPDIR and cache in SSTATE_DIR). It is a good idea to do so for three reasons :</description></item><item><title>HifiBerry OS configuration</title><link>https://percevalsa.github.io/posts/hifiberryos-configuration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percevalsa.github.io/posts/hifiberryos-configuration/</guid><description>HifiBerry OS Customizations Before moving to my custom version of piCorePlayer with my own Spotify extension I used to run HifiBerry on my raspberryPi. Here are some modifications I made to improve performances.
SSH for security I always harden all my Linux boxes. more on how to improve ssh security. Configure your ssh server to allow key authentication only.
Add my ssh key to to authorized key for easier remote control</description></item></channel></rss>